<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Blog Title</title>
  <subtitle>This is a longer description about your blog.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://example.com/blog/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://example.com/blog/" />
  <updated>2025-05-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://example.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Your Name</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>On dancing, slow movement, and blogging</title>
    <link href="https://example.com/blog/blog/firstpost/" />
    <updated>2025-05-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://example.com/blog/blog/firstpost/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-lackluster-origin-story&quot;&gt;My lackluster origin story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up rather reluctant to move. I was the kind of kid to stay indoors- reading, daydreaming, watching cartoons, or exercising my thumbs playing Pokemon on a Nintendo DS. Also, I&#39;m categorically bad at sports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For someone who voluntarily avoids physical activity, I never imagined I would love dancing. I was 13 when I discovered K-pop, which sparked my interest in movement. I was increasingly drawn to this genre because the dancing looked cool and expressive, albeit corny at times. As an Asian-American, I greatly appreciated how Asian idols defied the stereotype of Asians being geeky, awkward, unattractive, or lacking personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept my burgeoning interest in dance a secret from everyone, especially from my family. I thought I would be laughed at if anyone in my family knew how interested I was in dancing. So I didn&#39;t dance at all (except for occasional attemps at arm waves using the bathroom mirror 😅).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my teenage years and 20s, I regularly consumed dance content but I didn&#39;t really start learning dance until January 2021, at the age of 25. I enrolled at Steezy Studio, an online platform for hermits like me to wiggle around in the comfort of our homes. I started out learning a few choreographed hip-hop routines, flailing around alone in the garage. Eventually, I found house dance and now I regularly practice house 5 or 6 days a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;dancing-despite-insecurities&quot;&gt;Dancing despite insecurities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish I could say that I was dedicated to dance from 2021 to today. But I often let my insecurities get the better of me. A lot of things come up for me when I dance, especially my insecurities around being incompetent and lacking cooridination, rhythm, and confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s easy for me to drown in a stream of negative thinking. &lt;em&gt;I&#39;m too old to dance. I started too late. I have no talent. I should give up.&lt;/em&gt; Sometimes, the onslaught of shame is so loud and I can&#39;t seem to find the volume knob. But if I slow down and bring my mind back into my body, I feel better, by at least a quarter turn of the dial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had success of varying degrees with meditation, diet cleansing, and other self-help life hacks. But so far, the easiest way for me to breathe through my insecurities is through &lt;strong&gt;slow movement&lt;/strong&gt;. Slow running, slow qigong exercises, and slow practice of dance moves have all helped me observe my thoughts and let them be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m 29 now and I feel pressure to enter my thirties as someone who has more of her life sorted out. I have no ducks and no rows. I have no real plans. But in the meantime, I will keep dancing. My hope is to dance for as long as I am able to. 💃&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;blogging-for-learning&quot;&gt;Blogging for learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although experience is a wonderful teacher, I&#39;ve never been able to learn a darn thing the first time around. Learning for me requires a long gestation period, for repetition and reflection. I&#39;m starting this blog because I want to document what I&#39;m learning in dance, slow movement, and life in general. I find the poem &amp;quot;For a New Beginning&amp;quot; apt, excerpt below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though your destination is not yet clear
&lt;br&gt;You can trust the promise of this opening;
&lt;br&gt;Unfurl yourself into the grace of beginning
&lt;br&gt;That is at one with your life’s desire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awaken your spirit to adventure;
&lt;br&gt;Hold nothing back, learn to find ease in risk;
&lt;br&gt;Soon you will be home in a new rhythm,
&lt;br&gt;For your soul senses the world that awaits you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;- John O&#39; Donohue&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>